Ryan Workman

Summary

I am a full-stack engineer with experience in Ruby, Rails, SQL, React, Redux, and other JavaScript libraries. I am currently in charge of engineering and technology at a small product company in Venice, California. As lead engineer, I am focused on improving our 8+ year old codebase to handle ongoing scaling and sustainability challenges. In the past year, I have overhauled our legacy front-end patterns moving from RESTful MVC to a React-based single-page application increasing our server's request capacity by 400%.

Projects

Airbo (Web Application) - https://airbo.com HR communications platform for companies with 500+ employees

• Tech stack: Ruby, Rails, React, PostgreSQL

PokeApiV2 (Ruby Gem)

Ruby gem wrapper for https://pokeapi.co/api/v2/

• Tech stack: Ruby, Bundler, Net/HTTP

Employment

Airbo - Lead Engineer

May 2018 - Current

Venice, CA

- Scope and implement features redefining how employees experience corporate communications
- Overhaul legacy jQuery, RESTful front-end with React creating a single-page application and increasing request capacity by 400%

SlingTV - Front-End Engineer

May 2017 - May 2018

Denver, CO

- Work with architects and senior engineers creating the front-end engine managing all interactions on the web app's cart using React, Redux and Docker
- Add and maintain functionality on Dish's legacy Sling Television web application using AngularJS

Trelora - Full-Stack Engineer

Dec 2016 - Feb 2018

Denver, CO

 Internship and contract work developing new functionality using React and Ruby for internal file-storage API and signage app

KDVR Fox 31 Denver - News Producer

Jul 2014 - Jun 2016

Denver, CO

KPTV Fox 12 Oregon - News Producer Aug 2012 - May 2014 Portland, OR

Contact

(303) 815-0866 rdavid1099@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ryan-worman github.com/rdavid1099 ryan-workman.com

Education

Turing School of Software & Design
Certificate for Web Development
Ruby/Rails/JS - 2017
University of Northern Colorado
B.A. Journalism - 2011
Skills

Web Development

Front-End

- React
- Redux
- jQuery
- Angular
- JavaScript
- HTML/ CSS

Back-End

- Ruby/ Rails
- ActiveRecord
- Redis
- SQL

Server Management

- Bash/ Shell Script
- Heroku
- DigitalOcean Droplet
- Capistrano